{"Topic": "Maharashtra", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "With how many States does Maharashtra share its boundary?", "op1": "Four", "op2": "Five", "op3": "Six", "op4": "Seven", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "On which day was Maharashtra formed after separation from Bombay State?", "op1": "01 May 1960", "op2": "15 August 1947", "op3": "01 Nov 1956", "op4": "20 Oct 1962", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following is the first recipient of Jnanpith Award for Marathi literature?", "op1": "Vinda Karandikar", "op2": "Vishnu Khandekar", "op3": "Vasant Kanetkar", "op4": "Vijay Tendulkar", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which of the following places in Maharashtra is the Takht Shri Hazur Sahib located (one of the 5 important seats of Sikh authority)?", "op1": "Aurangabad", "op2": "Pune", "op3": "Nagpur", "op4": "Nanded", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "KD Jadhav from Maharashtra who won the first individual medal for India in the Olympics was associated with -", "op1": "Wrestling", "op2": "Boxing", "op3": "Weighlifting", "op4": "Swimming", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the first person from Maharashtra to become a Grandmaster in chess?", "op1": "Abhijit Kunte", "op2": "Swati Ghate", "op3": "Pravin Thipsay", "op4": "Tejas Bakre", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which city is the Bhandarkar Oriental Research Institute located?", "op1": "Pune", "op2": "Nagpur", "op3": "Mumbai", "op4": "Aurangabad", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a form of painting native to Maharashtra?", "op1": "Pattachitra", "op2": "Kalamkari", "op3": "Warli", "op4": "Madhubani", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following was the first Marathi talkie film?", "op1": "Ayodhyecha Raja", "op2": "Shyam Sundar", "op3": "Maya Machhindra", "op4": "Setu Bandhan", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the first recipient of the Maharashtra Bhushan Award?", "op1": "Lata Mangeshkar", "op2": "Bhimsen Joshi", "op3": "Sachin Tendulkar", "op4": "Purshottam Deshpande", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following sanctuaries in Maharashtra was notified in 2018?", "op1": "Koyna Wildlife Sanctuary", "op2": "Ghodazhari Wildlife Sanctuary", "op3": "Bhimashankar Wildlife Sanctuary", "op4": "Phansad Wildlife Sanctuary", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of these national parks is located within the city limits of Mumbai?", "op1": "Rajiv Gandhi National Park", "op2": "Jawaharlal Nehru Park", "op3": "Sanjay Gandhi National Park", "op4": "Gugamal National Park", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Ratnagiri is famous for the production of -", "op1": "Onions", "op2": "Grapes", "op3": "Bananas", "op4": "Mangoes", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Lasalgaon is a famous market place in Maharashtra for the trading of -", "op1": "Gold", "op2": "Onions", "op3": "Shares", "op4": "Cattle", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following districts of Maharashtra is well-known for its production of bananas?", "op1": "Jalgaon", "op2": "Ahmednagar", "op3": "Nashik", "op4": "Solapur", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following places in Maharashtra is famous for cotton bedsheets which have been given GI tag?", "op1": "Amaravati", "op2": "Solapur", "op3": "Kolhapur", "op4": "Sangli", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "At which of the following places is a branch of Mumbai High Court NOT located?", "op1": "Aurangabad", "op2": "Nagpur", "op3": "Pune", "op4": "Panaji", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the following is the author of the well-known book \u2018History of Dharmasastra\u2019?", "op1": "Pandurang Vaman Kane", "op2": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak", "op3": "Pandurang Sadashiv Sane", "op4": "R.G. Bhandarkar", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In which city of Maharashtra was an Indian Institute of Management established in the year 2015?", "op1": "Pune", "op2": "Nagpur", "op3": "Mumbai", "op4": "Nashik", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following established SNDT Women\u2019s University, the first university for women in India?", "op1": "RG Bhandarkar", "op2": "Dadabhai Naoroji", "op3": "Dondo Kesav Karve", "op4": "Bal Thackeray", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which is the largest district of Maharashtra in terms of area?", "op1": "Amaravati", "op2": "Nagpur", "op3": "Sangli", "op4": "Ahmednagar", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What percentage of population of Maharashtra is literate as per 2011 census?", "op1": "82.3%", "op2": "79.6%", "op3": "86.7%", "op4": "80.8%", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following districts has the lowest density?", "op1": "Chandrapur", "op2": "Sindhudurg", "op3": "Gadchiroli", "op4": "Ratnagiri", "Answer": 2}]}